# Luis A Ulloa

# Kennesaw GA | 816.267.3660

Email: luigi.ulloa@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/luisulloa/

Portfolio: https://luis-ulloa.github.io/ GitHub: https://github.com/luis-ulloa

#### **SUMMARY**

Data scientist with a strong analytical mindset and a technical background. Recently transitioned from supply chain and operations management to data science. Skilled in Python, data visualization, machine learning, and statistical analysis, with international experience in diverse industries.

#### **OBJECTIVE**

To apply my analytical and technical expertise in a data-focused role, contributing to impactful business decisions and innovative solutions.

# **SKILLS**

Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, SQL, Data Visualization, Data Cleaning and Preparation, Machine Learning, Statistical Analysis, Data Modeling.

#### **EDUCATION**

General Assembly: Immersive Data Science Bootcamp, Atlanta, GA

Master of International Business: Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA

B.E. Electrical Engineering: The City College of New York, New York, NY

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Lockheed Martin Corporation**

2011 to 2024

# Senior Subcontract Administrator, Marietta, GA (2015 to 2024)

- Developed pricing models in Excel to analyze proposals, driving strategic decision-making.
- Managed multimillion-dollar subcontracts, including successful vendor negotiations.
- Oversaw adoption of digital tools, enhancing operational efficiency.

# MRP Planning Analyst, Marietta, GA (2012 to 2015)

- Completed thorough BOM analysis of modification kits to ensure parts accuracy.
- Conducted parts availability analysis from SAP data sets to help address kit shortages.
- Scheduled kits per negotiated delivery timetable based on capacity and parts availability.

#### Supply Chain Analyst, Marietta, GA (2011 to 2012)

- Supported production functions for the C-130 program by ensuring timely availability of components.
- Coordinated with procurement to review delivery of parts, commitment dates and resolution of shortage issues.

# **DeWolff, Boberg & Associates**

2009 to 2011

#### Management Consultant, Atlanta, GA

- Coached production supervisors to use flow mapping and root-cause analysis for productivity gains.
- Designed Excel tools to track metrics, enabling teams to meet and exceed operational targets.
- Delivered process improvements in diverse industries across the USA and Latin America.

# Product Manager, GE Energy - Environmental Services, Kansas City, MO (2005 - 2009)

- Increased product sales by 71% in three years through application analysis and team collaboration.
- Saved 500K in potential warranty losses through negotiation and objective failure analysis.
- Drafted and published product articles in trade magazines to raise brand profile and highlight benefits to customers.

# Buyer, GE Rail - Global Signaling, Grain Valley, MO (2003 - 2005)

- Improved vendor delivery performance by 15% through strategic expectation-setting and communication.
- Worked cross-functionally with customer service team, suppliers and external third party to decrease payable issues from 1.5M to weekly average of 5K.

# Operations Management Leadership Program, GE Rail Headquarters, Erie, PA (2001 - 2003)

Two-year corporate leadership-training program consisting of four 6-month rotational assignments.

# Manufacturing Supervisor (Monterrey, NL - México)

- Led a team of 25 hourly employees.
- Partnered with workers to map processes, analyze outputs, and conduct root-cause analysis of recurring defects. This resulted in a 23% production increase on the field coils line and a 54% improvement on the armature coils line.

# Reliability Engineer

Developed engineering specifications to prevent connector mismatches.

#### **Line Supervisor**

Led a team of 12 hourly employees.

#### **Operations Support Facilitator**

- Finalized implementation of online repair cost tracking tool and trained hourly employees.
- Redesigned workstation to reduce safety problems.